Hello everyone. In this video, we will implement UT with Canata.
First, we will have the list of modules that need to implement UT with Cantata.
In this video, we will implement UT for the first module.
Before implementing UT for Cantata, we will be provided the database files.
There will be a header folder in this database. It will hold all header files that could be used in the .C files.
In addition, it will contain the Cantata folders for each module.
At this point, when implementing UT in Cantata, we only need to copy the header file and the corresponding Cantata file for each C file.
In this video, I will use UT_008, then I will copy header file and UT_008 file to my Workspace
After copying to my Workspace, I will open Canata
After opening Canata, we will change it to C/C++ mode
Then we will open two folders, header and UT folder
Cantata can release folder, but we can delete it and do it again
First I will do release
I will select the file that I want to do, then select release
When you see the line has "WinMan@16" in console window, it means that my release is success
Now I can create a test case for this C file
I can type the name of the C file, then click on the test case
The name of the test case will usually start with A test, then the name of the C file
Next, I will choose the COVID rule, which is Reboot on Equip
At this time, it will reboot all the values ​​such as C0, C1, C1C
I will choose Finish
Then I choose Test Case
On this side, Canada has not created a test case yet
I will create a test case for this module
Here I will create a test case for the first function, which is this function
Copy the function and select this function
This is a test case model, it will have the name of the test case
Where it is used to attach the value of global variables
Input variables
And
It will be the place where
I attach the value of global variables after it has been calculated
Next is the test case's Deprivation
When I go to which part, I can click here
Next is Inspector Call
For UT, I will set the code line for a single C module
So there are functions that will be executed in other modules
So here I will do stop for these functions
And do not run the code
Actually for the top functions
So here it will have all the
Next is the F function that I should call to
And finally is the check function
With this check function, it will check all the global variables in the FACI report
Including the static variables
Return from the value of this function
And this function I can
Actually stop it
So the stop work will be done at the bottom of the test case
I can search for the name of the function here
And
This function will have the value of Win8
So
To
I will do this
This condition while the return value of this function will be 1
And I can stop the value
For the next
This is the name of the function
That I can call it
When I call it, it will have the value of Win8
Win8
2sc to this condition
After 2sc, it will continue to run to this line
Now it meets a return line
This return line will have the word
Enum, so we can
Create a stop return for it
then
In the same way
Next, there is the static
It will be valued at this end
In this line, we can also stop
This is a bool that can store values ​​back to it
Do or False
We can create two values ​​back
One is true, the other is false
In this case, we can add values ​​back to it
It also contains the above values ​​stops
This line has a shape value that we can stop according to the false set
Because in this set, we need to call the TrueScale of this line
We need to call the TrueScale of this line
I will give the value of its value as true
In the next step, the value of this static object is again reduced by the value of its value
Just like that
I will do the same for the value of its value
And the name of this object
I have set the value of this object by true
And the value of this object is reduced by the value of its value
It is now in the true state of this object
At this time, it will perform
According to the true state of the condition
It will perform call to this function
This function is an array, so it doesn't need any value
I just need to check it
Call to is OK
And the value of this object will be reattached by the value of the answer value of this object
I will also set this object as an array
Its return value will be true or false
I will introduce it as true
Then, the return value of the variable
The return value of the variable false
So the condition below this is also completely released
That means this array will be called
I will now set this variable to true
And the value of this object is 0
Next, because it's already in the logic tool of this one, so it will form a post
I put it in this point
And finally, in this function, it will perform on this line
This line has a variable value
Then I have a variable value for it
The same way as the value of the stop section
Here I type the name of it
So when it gets to this point, I will also type its name
At this time, I can comment that I will call the true scale of this condition
I have completed all the inputs, commands, and test scales, then I will continue to convert all of them
First of all, I will convert all of them
Then it will return by the value of the stop-nand value
When I said that the value returned will be 1
So here I will expect it to be this value
This value means that the value returned is 1
Similarly, this is a static piece
So I will also set the value returned for it
This static piece is attached here
And attached here, I will get the final attachment of it
Then I returned the value for this stop as true
This means that the value of this piece after returning
It will be fixed as true
Then it will be false
Next is the test-interrupted variable
This variable will receive the value returned of this function
When I set the value returned for this function
It will be true
So the value returned of this variable will also be true
And finally, the value returned of this function
When calling this function
Its value will be set by the value of the stop-nand value
And when I set the value for it by 1
Then at this time, the value returned of this variable will also be true
So all the static and global variables are normal
The value returned value has been checked
At this time you can run your Test-key
To see the result like that
I will choose Run Code
I choose the code that I want to test
I choose Test Game
In Console, I can check all of myヘープ
I can check all of myヘープ
That means, my japan trade is good
My foreign exchange ratio is good
Besides, I can't read
My test case has covered the conditions by CodeCoveredViewer
Here, according to my command, I will want to cover the tool case of this condition
So now, in this part, CodeCoveredViewer also shows that I have entered my tool case
Next, in CodeCoveredResult, I can also see
Here, it will display the total number of C0, C1, and I will use it to cover
And I will also show the total number of C0, C1, and I will use it to cover
Now, I will test my first test case to meet the purpose
Similarly, I will test my first test case for the whole function
as well as the test case for the second function
Let's have a look
Now, I will run my motherboard one more time
As you can see, in CodeCoveredViewer, all the conditions are the same
And in CodeCoveredViewer, all the indexes have been set to 100%
Because I have done all the UT for this module
Then, I will choose my module to create a ZEN variable
In the variable, it will also show my indexes
For example, C0 is 100%, C1 is 100%, and CEC is also 100%
Now I have to load the folder
And if I want to create a ZEN variable, I can do it here
And I can check the result after creating the UT in CodeCoveredViewer
Result
Test Report
It will show the overall result of my code
Summary
And my test case is BatchFL
Here I will be Batch
My coverage will be 100%
And below it will also have a report for each test case
Next is Test Summary
Here my Test Summary overall result will also be Batch
And all the indexes will also be 100%
And now I have finished creating the UT with CodeCoveredViewer
Thank you for watching